Perkins, James Secor Additional Papers 6027
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
James Secor Perkins Additional Papers
1916-1970
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Perkins, James Secor
6027
2.5 cubic feet
2.5 linear ft.
Papers.
5767417
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, June 30, 2014
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, August 18, 2015
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 6002 AV: James S. Perkins Collection of Movie Film Studies of Shop Operations
Gilbreth, Frank B. (Frank Bunker), 1911-; Gilbreth, Lillian Moller, 1878-1972; Perkins, James Secor; Hawthorne Works -- Archives; Western Electric Company -- Archives
5767417
- The American Image of Success 1961 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- ASIM Jon Rating 1960-1964 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Assuring a Dynamic Organization (Box 1, Folder 3)
- The Effect of Additional Directional Control on the Time for Shoulder Movement Experiment No. 13, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- The Motion Study Laboratory Experiment: The Eye (Box 1, Folder 5)
- The Eye (Box 1, Folder 6)
- The Eye Report (Box 1, Folder 7)
- The Executive I like to Work For (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Famous Firsts 1964-1966 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Gilbreth Medal 1945 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Haskins Horizontal Taping Machines (Box 1, Folder 11)
- The Hawthorne Merit Rating Plan 1946 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- An Introduction to the Theory and Application of Motion Study 1944 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- An Investigation of Some Hand Motions used in Faculty Work 1936 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Iowa Skill Study (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Iowa Skill Study Photographs (Box 1, Folder 16)
  Scope and Contents
  18 Photographs
- Western Electric Iowa Skill Study (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Iowa Skill Study Speech Copies 1941 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- The Microphone 1946 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Milestones of Managements 1964 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Motion Economy in Manufacturing Operations 1938 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Motion Studies Make Plants Safer 1937 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Motion Study (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Movements of the Body Members Their Symbols and Definitions (Box 1, Folder 24)
- New Era for Work Simplification, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Production Control Load Board for Danvilly Plant Operation 1961 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Production Control Systems Portfolio 1945 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Record of Prints Prepared for Motion Study Courses and Conferences (Box 1, Folder 28)
- The Results of the PEG Board Dexterity Tests 1937 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Selecting Women for Shop Work 1932 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Society for the Advancement or Management News Bulletin 1945-1946 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Speeches by James S. Perkins 1947-1948 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- A Study of the Development of Skill During Performance or a Factory Operation 1941 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- A Study of the Effects of Plastics of the Elements of a Factory Operation 1948 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Time Standard No. 16. 2 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Advances Management Journal 1964 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- NAPMSB: Bricklaying System, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  5 Photographs
- Gilbreth Centennial 1968 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Gilbreth Classification Code Book 1948 (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Cheaper By the Dozen 1949 (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Gilberth Correspondence 1917-1918 (Box 1, Folder 41)
- The Conservation of the World's Teeth: A New Occupation of the World's Soldiers 1917 (Box 1, Folder 42)
- Danville Industrial Club 1961 (Box 1, Folder 43)
- The Effect of Motion Study Upon the Workers 1916 (Box 1, Folder 44)
- NAPTA: Fatigue Study [Folder 1 of 2], 1921 (Box 1, Folder 45)
- NAPTA: Fatigue Study [Folder 2 of 2], 1940 (Box 1, Folder 46)
- Gilbreth Film Presentation Transcripts [Folder 1 of 2] 1968 (Box 1, Folder 47)
- Gilbreth Film Presentation Transcript 1968 [Folder 2 of 2] (Box 1, Folder 48)
- Gilbreth Film Notes 1968 (Box 1, Folder 49)
- Gilbreth Film Project, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 50)
- The Original Films of Frank, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 51)
- Gilbreth Flyers 1944-1968 (Box 1, Folder 52)
- The Gilbreths: Partners 1984 (Box 1, Folder 53)
- Gilbreth Photographs, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  11 Photographs
- Gilbreth Revisited 1966 (Box 1, Folder 55)
- Lillian Gilbreth 1954-1972 (Box 1, Folder 56)
- Management Methods and Principles of Frank B. Gilbreth, Inc. 1923 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- More Bricks Less Sweat, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Motion and Time Study Applicants 1942 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Motion Modeled 1916-1935 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Motion Study for the Crippled Soldier 1915 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Motion Study in Hospitals, 1915-1916 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Normal Lives for the Disabled 1945 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Gilbreth Notes Binder 1 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Gilbreth Notes Binder 2 [Folder 1 of 2] (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Gilbreth Notes Binder 2 [Folder 2 of 2], 1968 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Notes in Motion Studies in Medicine, 1916-1919 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- The Place of Psychology in Industry 1921 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- The Practical Kitchen (Box 2, Folder 13)
- PESTACO News 1962 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Teaching Surgery by the Moving Picture 1919 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- The Three Position Pain of Promotion 1916 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Tribute to Frank Bunker Gilbreth 1944 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- The Years of Scientific Management 1923 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Are the Classics Really Out of Date? 1969 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- The Blue Book of Fair Rates of Pay - 1991 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Business Organization (Box 2, Folder 21)
- A Company's job Analysis, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Correspondence 1961-1970 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Do Consultants Really Help? 1977 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Flyers, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- For Productivity, use Sensitivity (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Frederick W. Taylor: The Birth of Scientific Management 1881-1911 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Fringe Benefit Study 1980 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- The GM Lordstown Revolt 1979 (Box 2, Folder 29)
- The Gellerman Motivation and Productivity Film Series 1967 (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Georgia Printer 1982-1983 (Box 2, Folder 31)
- Here's the Solution to your Problems (Box 2, Folder 32)
- How Ratio Analysis Improves Profits 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 33)
- Human Nature and Organization Realities (Box 2, Folder 34)
- The Impact of the Organization: Chris Argyres (Box 2, Folder 35)
- Inter/Com Article Galley 1973 (Box 2, Folder 36)
- The Leader Looks at the Consulting Process 1961 (Box 2, Folder 37)
- Let's Go: Down With Downtime (Box 2, Folder 38)
- Man-Equipment System Task for Apollo 1968 (Box 2, Folder 39)
- Managing in a Changing World 1964 (Box 2, Folder 40)
- Motion Analysis: What it can do for Productivity 1973 (Box 2, Folder 41)
- The Name of the Game is Productivity 1969 (Box 2, Folder 42)
- PAR Production Services (Box 2, Folder 43)
- PAR: Production Standards for Phillipsburg Inserters 1977 (Box 2, Folder 44)
- PIA Flyers (Box 2, Folder 45)
- PIA Bulletin, 1961-1971 (Box 2, Folder 46)
- PIA Review 1964 (Box 2, Folder 47)
- Percent of Fold Time (Box 2, Folder 48)
- Perkins Biography 1988 (Box 2, Folder 49)
- Plant Efficiency Peaks From Economy of Motion 1973 (Box 2, Folder 50)
- Plaque Presented to James S. Perkins 1978 (Box 2, Folder 51)
- The President's connection 1983 (Box 2, Folder 52)
- Production Control (Box 2, Folder 53)
- Production Management Seminar, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 54)
- Production Standards Program in A Medium Size Shop 1970 (Box 2, Folder 55)
- Production Standards' Value Told to Printers 1970 (Box 2, Folder 56)
- The Professional Manager 1964 (Box 2, Folder 57)
- Quality: The Us Drives to catch Up 1982 (Box 2, Folder 58)
- Ratio Study 1971 (Box 2, Folder 59)
- SAM News International 1968-1976 (Box 2, Folder 60)
- Saint of Science 1965 (Box 2, Folder 61)
- Seminar Assignment 1975 (Box 2, Folder 62)
- Sam PAR Production Standards, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 63)
- Toronto Profit Improvement Seminar 1971 (Box 2, Folder 64)
- Up with Productivity 1973 (Box 2, Folder 65)
- What a New Plant Layout can do for you 1970 (Box 2, Folder 66)
- What is Fair Pay? 1972 (Box 2, Folder 67)
- What is PAR? 1968 (Box 2, Folder 68)
- What makes a Worker want to work?, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 69)
- Workplace Design 1969 (Box 2, Folder 70)
- Youtoo, Can be A "Natural Born Leaders (Box 2, Folder 71)
- Origins of Industrial Engineering 1988 (Box 2, Folder 72)
- Harper's Dictionary of the Graphic Arts 1963 (Box 2, Folder 73)
- Paragraph 1972-1979 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- PAR-Lance 1966 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- PAR-Lance 1967 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- PAR-Lance 1968 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- PAR-Lance 1969 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- PAR-Lance 1970-1971 (Box 3, Folder 6)